A Guide to the Papers of Orland E. White, (1911) 1935-1955
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Orland E. White (1911) 1935-1955
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
12767
This collection consists of 250 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.)
Acquisition Information
The collection was presented to the Library by Mrs. W. Ralph Singleton, Charlottesville, Virginia, on 1981 October 14.
Scope and Content Information
The papers of Orland Emile White consist of ca. 250 items, (1911) 1935-1955, chiefly pertaining to his tenure as professor of agricultural biology and director of the Blandy Experimental Farm at the University of Virginia. The papers include correspondence and miscellaneous papers relating to several University of Virginia departments, letters of recommendation, examinations, and quizzes given by White. In addition, the papers include near print drafts of White's "Chronological Outline of the Development of Genetics and Its Cytological Aspects." Also included are notes taken by White during lectures given by Wilhelm Ludwig Johannsen (1857-1927), a Danish botanist and geneticist who was known for his experiments leading to his development of the pure-line theory of plant biology.
Arrangement
The papers are arranged following their original foldering, and contents are in reverse chronological order. Folder headings have been modified and are arranged alphabetically.
Contents List
- Biology Book Lists and correspondence 1951, 1953, n.d., 7 items
- Biology Department 1950-1955, n.d., 15 items
- Biology Department: Examinations and quizzes given by Orland E. White 1935-1954, 69 items
- Biology Department: Miller Professor correspondence 1952 Dec, 8 items
- Blandy Experimental Farm: Jacques Rappaport Papers 1949-1955, 15 items
- Bursar's Office 1931-1954, 10 items
- "Chronological Outline of the Development of Genetics and Its Cytological Aspects" by Orland E. White n.d., 5 items
- Faculty 1950-1954, n.d., 20 items
- Notes of Lectures by Wilhelm Ludwig Johannsen re Genetics 1911-1912, 2 items
- Notes of philosophy course lectures, South Dakota State College 1911, n.d., 10 items
- Letters of Recommendations 1928 (1942-1943) 1948, 24 items
  (Restricted)
- Miscellaneous Papers 1935-1955, 16 items
- Personnel Department 1952-1955, 7 items
- President's Office 1950-1955, 16 items
- State of Virginia - correspondence 1930-1952, 14 items